# NICHOLAS DECHANT

Phone: (425) 922-1585 · Email: dchant@uw.edu · linkedin.com/in/NicholasDeChant · nickdec.github.io

A technically skilled individual with BI experience and 5+ years working as a customer service and consulting professional. Background includes relational database implementation, multi-dimensional design, data mining, and data visualization across the Microsoft SQL Server platform. Current Data Analytics student seeking internships or entry level opportunities.

# **EDUCATION**

**BA**, Mathematics

**Spring 2011 - Spring 2015** 

University of Washington

**BAS, Data Analytics** 

Fall 2021

Bellevue College

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

**Tableau Desktop Specialist** | Tableau Software | February 2020 **Exam 98-364: Database Fundamentals** | Microsoft | July 2019

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Guest Services Associate, Hilton**

June 2017 - Present

- Create reservations, check-in guests, and ensure all guests requests are achieved accordingly.
- Arrange transportation services for guests to local businesses, restaurants, and airport.
- Maintain top tier customer service and a high level of professionalism in a team environment.

#### Support Manager, D.C.S.

March 2015 - January 2017

- Assisted with Close-Range Photogrammetry workshops, provided by DCS at customer's facilities.
- Trained clients with photogrammetric software and provided maintenance services.
- Provided services to customers, such as order placement or account information.

### TECHNOLOGIES and SKILLS

**Programming**: T-SQL, Java, Python, R, PHP, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery/JSON **Software**: SQL Server Management Studio, MongoDB Compass, Rstudio, Tableau Desktop, Docker, Visual Studio, jGrasp, Filezilla

### **PROJECTS**

### **Data Management**

- Designed relational databases, normalized tables, imported data, and used for reporting.
- Wrote a python script to take user input, query MongoDB and return results in a .csv file.
- Developed data mining models in Visual Studio to evaluate datasets and report trends.

#### **Data Visualization**

- Used best practices and charting techniques for interactive dashboard visualizations in Tableau.
- Cleaned, transformed and prepared .csv and PDF data files using Tableau Prep.
- Produced basic charts in Microsoft Power BI.

#### **Data and Software Programming**

- Applied linear regression techniques in R to model movie popularity based off weekly rank data.
- Made a Fifteen Puzzle webpage game using advanced JavaScript and basic HTML.
- Created an HTML validator for any input HTML document using stacks and queues.